Love will give you life.
Guillermo del Toro's Pinocchio is a animation, fantasy,
adventure film directed by Mark Gustafson.
During the rise of fascism in Mussolini's Italy, a wooden boy brought
magically to life struggles to live up to his father's expectations.
Cricket (voice), played by Ewan McGregor.
Geppetto (voice), played by David Bradley.
Pinocchio / Carlo (voice), played by Gregory Mann.
Priest (voice), played by Burn Gorman.
Podesta (voice), played by Ron Perlman.
Dottore (voice), played by John Turturro.
Guillermo del Toro's Pinocchio (or simply Pinocchio) is a 2022 animated musical dark fantasy film directed by Guillermo del Toro
and Mark Gustafson, from a story by Matthew Robbins and del Toro, and a screenplay by del Toro and Patrick McHale.
It is loosely based on Carlo Collodi's 1883 Italian novel The Adventures of Pinocchio, with the
title character's design strongly influenced by illustrator Gris Grimly's work.
Set in Fascist Italy during the interwar period, the story follows Pinocchio, a
wooden puppet who comes to life as the son of his carver, Geppetto.
The film stars the voice of Gregory Mann as Pinocchio and David Bradley as Geppetto, alongside Ewan McGregor, Burn Gorman, Ron
Perlman, John Turturro, Finn Wolfhard, Cate Blanchett, Tim Blake Nelson, Christoph Waltz, and Tilda Swinton.
Pinocchio was the final film credited to Gustafson before his death in 2024.
A longtime passion project for del Toro, who considers that no other character ever "had as deep of a
personal connection to [him]" as Pinocchio, the film is dedicated to the memories of his parents.
It was originally announced in 2008 with a release in 2013 or 2014.
However, it went into development hell.
In January 2017, McHale was announced to co-write the screenplay, but production was
suspended in November 2017 as no studios were willing to provide financing.
It was revived the following year after being acquired by Netflix.
Pinocchio premiered at the 66th BFI London Film Festival on October 15, 2022.
It was released in select theaters on November 9, and
began streaming on Netflix on December 9.
The film received widespread critical acclaim for its direction, writing, voice performances, animation,
production design, musical numbers, and faithfulness in retaining the darkness of the source material.
Among its numerous accolades, Pinocchio won Best Animated Feature category at the Academy
Awards, BAFTA Awards, Golden Globe Awards, Critic's Choice Awards and PGA Awards.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
italy, fascism, greed, woodcutter.
The tone is dark and emotional.